<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ranor on Ranor</title>
        <link>https://ranoriginals.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Ranor on Ranor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        
        
            <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
        
        
            <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:10:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
        <atom:link href="https://ranoriginals.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>Zhuoran Zhang</title>
                <link>https://ranoriginals.github.io/about/</link>
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
                
                <guid>https://ranoriginals.github.io/about/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;M.S. Candidate&lt;/em&gt;,  Geophysics, Nanjing University, Nanjing, China, 2018-present. (Adviser: &lt;a href=&#34;https://es.nju.edu.cn/ryy/list.htm&#34;&gt;Youyi Ruan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPA: 4.54/5.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;B.S&lt;/em&gt;.  Geology, Nanjing University, Nanjing, China, 2014-2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPA: 4.43/5.0 (Top 5%)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-interests&#34;&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Induced seismicity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lithospheric Structure of Southeastern Tibet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-experiences&#34;&gt;Research Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shear wave velocity and attenuation imaging of the lithosphere in southeastern Tibet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilize Two Plane Wave method to invert Rayleigh wave phase velocity and attenuation coefficient simultaneously for 4 subregions in SE Tibet. It’s a rare attempt to apply two plane wave method in areas where the attenuation effect is not so significant. Write scripts to process 144 events recorded by 350 stations data and debug the inversion programs. The preliminary attenuation results imply that the lithosphere in the southeastern Tibetan Plateau has a stratified rheological structure with a weak mid-lower crust, probably caused by partial melting, on top of a strong uppermost mantle. (Oct 2019 – Present)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The relationship between Hutubi gas storage’s operation and the surrounding seismic activities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilized the Match-Filter technique to detect small earthquakes and expand the earthquake catalog. Wrote scripts to process the whole year continuous data of about 30 stations in 2016. Compared the seismicity before and after the completion of gas storage, found that the pressure of it has an enhanced influence on surrounding seismicity, especially the pressure increased beyond a certain threshold about 22MPa. (July 2018 – Oct 2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rupture process of the 2016 Kumamoto Earthquake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilized the time-domain back-projection Method to investigate the rupture process of the 2016 Kumamoto Earthquake, and found that crustal structure controlled the energy release of the earthquake. Wrote scripts based on MATLAB to process raw data recorded by USArray and realized the multi-channel cross-correlation algorithm to determine optimum relative delay times for seismograms. (Mar 2017 – Jun 2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-publications&#34;&gt;Research Publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zhuoran, Z.&lt;/strong&gt;, Bin, W., Zonghang, S. et al., 2020, Effects of the Hutubi underground gas storage in 2016 on the surrounding seismic activities, &lt;em&gt;Chinese Journal of Geophysics (In Chinese)&lt;/em&gt;, 63(9): 3387-3397. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6038/cjg2020O0138&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting Abstracts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zhuoran, Z.&lt;/strong&gt; and Youyi, R., Shear attenuation of the lithosphere beneath the southeastern Tibetan plateau. &lt;em&gt;American Geophysical Union, Fall Meeting 2020&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zhuoran, Z.&lt;/strong&gt;, Zonghang, S., Tao, W. and Youyi, R., Effects of the hutubi underground gas storage in2016 on the surrounding seismic activities. &lt;em&gt;Annual Meeting of Chinese Geoscience Union, Beijing, China, 2018&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operation Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Linux, Mac OS, Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : Python, Shell, Fortran, MATLAB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seismological Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : GMT, SAC, SPECFEM2D/3D, Obspy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Seismic Instruments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broadband Seismograph&lt;/em&gt; : RefTek-130/130s data logger and Guralp CMG-40T/3T sensor, Nanometrics Trillium 40s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Short Period Nodes&lt;/em&gt; : Fairfield Zland 3C nodes, Smartsolo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strong Motion Seismograph&lt;/em&gt; : Kinematics Etna2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;field-work&#34;&gt;Field Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illuminating Nanjing University Xianlin Campus.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed over 100 Fairfield Zland 3C nodes in campus. Assisted in designing the seismic acquisition system combined with short period nodes, optical fibers, strong-motion seismographs, seismic air-gun source and vibrator trucks. Completed data collection, organization and backup. (2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geological Survey in Huizhou, Guangdong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed over 200 Fairfield Zland 3C and Smartsolo short period nodes and 30 broadband seismic stations across the Lianhuashan Fault zone. Designed the seismic acquisition system in my district and completed data collection, organization and backup. Wrote a guide book to the layout of short period nodes dense array. (2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChinArray Phase III.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed and maintained broadband seismic stations in the Liaodong Peninsula and Inner Mongolia Province. (2018-2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-experiences&#34;&gt;Teaching Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Seismology, Teaching Assistant, Nanjing University, 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content: Quick Start with GMT 5.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploration Seismology, Teaching Assistant, Nanjing University, 2018&amp;amp;2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content: Quick Start with SPECFEM2D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Posts</title>
                <link>https://ranoriginals.github.io/posts/</link>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 21:59:54 +0800</pubDate>
                
                <guid>https://ranoriginals.github.io/posts/</guid>
                <description></description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
